frenchestateagents.com 2018-11-22

# Privacy

##  Data covered by this statement 

This Privacy Statement applies to the use and processing of personal information collected and used by Leggett Immobilier and its agents. 

By using Leggett Immobilier websites and mobile applications or otherwise providing your personal information to Leggett Immobilier, you agree to the collection, use and sharing of your information in accordance with this statement. Please read this Privacy Statement carefully. 

“Personal information” is information, or any combination of separate pieces of information, that could be used to identify you. 

Should you have any queries in respect of this statement or our use of personal data, please contact Leggett Immobilier Data Protection Officer at [ cil@leggett.fr ](mailto:cil@leggett.fr)

##  Data Collection 

We may collect information about you from a variety of sources. This includes information we collect directly from you; information we collect when you visit our sites, view our online content or use our mobile applications or other services; and information we collect about you from other sources. 

###  Information we collect directly from you 

We collect information directly from you when you choose to participate in our offers and programs, create an account on our websites or in our mobile applications, call or email us or our agents, or otherwise provide information directly to us during viewings for instance. The following are examples of information we may collect directly from you: 

  * Name 
  * Email address 
  * Postal address 
  * Username and password 
  * Telephone number 
  * Date of birth 
  * Demographic information 
  * Payment information (such as a credit card) and bank account details 
  * Future communication preferences 
  * Telephone number and recordings when you call our customer service line 

###  Information automatically collected online 

####  Cookies 

We use cookies and other technologies to collect information when you visit our sites, view our online advertisements or promotions, or use our mobile applications or other services. 

A cookie is a small file placed on your device when you visit a site that can be understood by the site that issued the cookie. We use the information collected by cookies to remember who you are to log you in and your preferences, to provide you advertisements, offers or other content tailored to your interests and to assess how our sites are used. You can accept or decline cookies through your browser settings. To learn more, please look at the cookie settings available in your specific web browser(s). Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to use all of the features of our sites or other websites and online services. 

The following are examples of information we may collect with these technologies : 

  * Information about your device browser and operating system. 
  * IP address 
  * Web pages you view 
  * Links you click 
  * Leggett Immobilier emails you open (Property Alerts, Newsletters, Industry updates) 

In conjunction with gathering information through cookies and Javascript, our web servers may log information such as your device type, operating system type, browser type, domain, and other system settings, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time zone where your device is located. We also may record information such as the address of the web page that referred you to our sites and the IP address of the device you use to connect to our sites. We also may send instructions to your device using JavaScript or other computer languages to gather the sorts of information described above and other details about your interactions with our sites. 

###  Social Networks and Third-Party Plug-ins 

Leggett Immobilier’s websites may include plugins from social networks or other third parties. An example of a plugin is the Facebook “Like” button. Where legally permitted, these plugins may communicate with and send information to the party that provided the plugin, even if you do not click on the plugin. This information may include your IP address, information about your browser and device, and the address of the web page you are visiting on our site. Loading, using or clicking the plugins may also place, read and transmit cookies. These cookies may contain a unique identifier the social network or third party assigns to you. The loading, functionality and your use of the plugins are governed by the privacy statement and terms of the party that provided the plugin. 

The providers of third-party plug-ins and widgets (see § plugins) on our sites, such as embedded videos and social media sharing tools, may use automated means to collect information regarding your use of the sites and your interactions with the plug-ins and widgets. We may also receive information you have made available to those third party services, including the geographic location of your mobile device and other information about you (such as name, email address, gender, location, time zone, languages, social media profile URL, personal website URL, biographical information, birthday, photo, list of devices, education history, work history, hometown, interests, current city, political views, favourite athlete and teams, relationship status and information, religion, name of significant other, and certain security settings information) and your contacts on those services. This information is subject to the privacy policies or notices of the third party providers of the plug-ins and widgets. 

###  Social Network and Third-Party Login 

Leggett Immobilier’s websites may allow you to log in using a social network or other third-party account. An example of a third-party login is “Log in with Facebook.” Logging into one of our sites with your social network or other third-party account may allow us to gather information that you give us permission to access from that social network or third party. The login feature may also transfer information to the social network or third party, such as your username and password, to authenticate you. The social network or third party may also automatically collect information such as your IP address, information about your browser and device, and the address of the web page you are visiting on our site. The login feature may also place and read cookies from that third party that may contain a unique identifier the social network or other third party assigns to you. The functionality of and your use of the login is governed by the privacy statement and terms of the party that provided the login functionality. 

###  User Generated Content 

Please remember that any information you submit or post as user-generated content to Social Media sites become public information. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal, financial or other information in such submissions or posts. Leggett Immobilier cannot prevent others from using such information in a manner that may violate this Privacy Statement, the law, or your personal privacy and safety. Leggett Immobilier is not responsible for the results of such postings. 

##  Use of data 

###  By Leggett Immobilier 

We use the information we collect to provide you products, offers and services, to deliver to you advertisements, offers or other content tailored to your interests, and to conduct other Leggett Immobilier business operations. The following are examples of how we may use the information we collect: 

  * Answer your questions or respond to your requests. 
  * Develop new products and services. 
  * Enrol you in programs, or offers that you request. 
  * Create and manage your account. 
  * Process payment for purchases or other services. 
  * Protect against or identify possible fraudulent transactions. 
  * Send you email and/or postal messages with information about Leggett Immobilier brands and other content we think may be of interest to you. 
  * Develop and provide marketing tailored to your interests, including interest-based marketing. 
  * Personalise your experience on our websites by presenting products and information tailored to you. 
  * Allow you to participate in social sharing on our websites. 
  * Analyse the use of, and develop, our products, services and marketing. Enforce our Terms and Conditions and otherwise manage our business. 

Leggett Immobilier will only process your information in pursuance of our legitimate interest if we receive any requests related to, for example, a product or service, a call-back, or specific marketing materials; we will use your personal information to fulfil your request. Where we need to manage your account and protect you against or identify possible fraudulent transactions, we will do so in accordance with our legal obligation placed on us under law. You will of course be informed if such situation should arise. 

###  Promotional Email Communications 

Leggett Immobilier email communications consist of, but are not limited to: 

  * Property Alerts 
  * Newsletters 
  * Satisfaction Surveys 
  * Regional Emails 
  * Journey emails 
  * Property tips and Advice 
  * Property Show invitations 
  * Electronic version of our bi-annual magazine and information on how to feature in it, 
  * Regional property information 
  * Property marketing information. 

You can stop receiving promotional email messages from Leggett Immobilier by following the opt-out instructions provided in any such message you receive. 

###  By Third-Parties 

The success of our business depends on your trust, and we do not rent, exchange or sell your personal information to marketers outside of Leggett Immobilier. We do share your personal information for the well functioning of our company, for legal requirement but also for business development. 

###  Third-party service providers 

We engage third-party service providers to perform a variety of business operations on our behalf. In so doing, we may share your personal information with them. We provide our service providers with only the personal information they need in order to perform the services we request, and we contractually require that they protect this information appropriately and not use it for any other purpose. 

For example, we may rely on a 3rd party service provider to : 

  * Develop our property portfolio (partners) 
  * Develop our visibility (portals, partners) 
  * Host our sites and deliver our email or other communications. 
  * Subcontract our accounting 
  * Subcontract ou informatics department 
  * Maintain our electronic devices 
  * Formalize our transaction (Notary, town hall, urbanism service) 
  * Analyse our data, sometimes combined with data from other sources, to send you communications. 
  * Conduct research and analyse data to improve our products, services and sites. 
  * Perform other services that we request. 

You can oppose the sharing of your personal data for business development (partners, portals, …) 

###  Other 

We may transfer your personal information : 

  * To our capital-intensive partners after obtaining your consent 
  * To protect, defend or exercise the rights and property of Leggett Immobilier (including enforcing our Terms and Conditions). 
  * When required by law and/or government authorities. 

###  Data Transfers 

We may transfer the personal information we collect about you to recipients in countries other than the country in which the information originally was collected. Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. When we transfer your information to recipients in other countries: 

  * we will perform those transfers in accordance with the requirements of applicable law; 
  * we will protect the transferred personal information in accordance with this Privacy Statement. 

###  Aggregated and non-personal information. 

We share aggregated and/or anonymous information that does not identify you for Leggett Immobilier business purposes. For example, we may disclose the number of visitors to Leggett Immobilier sites or services. We may also share aggregated and/or anonymous information with our business partners for their own business purposes. 

##  Data Storage 

###  Personal Information Retention Period 

We will retain Personal Information for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Privacy Statement, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law. The legal data retention period is of 5 years starting at the end of the business relationship, concerning data and documents relating to the identity of the customer. This retention period do not modify the regulation regarding the retention period for other professional documents, and in particular the 10 year period enforced by the law n°70-9 of the 2nd of January 1970 regarding documents that are specific to our profession (namely register of mandates, mandates, …) 

###  Information Security 

Leggett Immobilier is committed to keeping personal information secure. We have implemented technical, administrative and physical procedures designed to protect personal information from loss, misuse or alteration, but also against a possible malevolent use of said information. 

We limit access to personal information to those who have a business need. 

##  YOU AND YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION 

To the extent provided for by applicable law, you have certain rights in respect of the management of the personal data we hold about you. 

###  Access 

We take steps to keep your personal information accurate. Many Leggett Immobilier programs provide access to view or update personal information you provided when you registered online. Leggett Immobilier does not charge for this service and responds to reasonable requests in an appropriate time frame. 

###  Other rights 

To the extent provided by applicable law, you have the right to request rectification of your personal data; to obtain restriction of the processing of personal data; to object to the processing of personal data (including direct marketing) and to data portability. To exercise any of these rights, please contact us at cil@leggett.fr 

###  Consent / Complaints 

Where you have provided consent for our processing of your personal data, you may withdraw that consent at any time by contacting us at cil@leggett.fr. We will cease processing your personal data as soon as reasonably practicable following our receipt of your withdrawal. 

Likewise, your claims regarding the processing of your personal information must be sent via email to cil@leggett.fr 

###  Updates to our Privacy Statement 

Leggett Immobilier reserves the right to amend, update and change their privacy statement at their own discretion while respecting the applicative laws. All updates to Leggett Immobiliers Privacy Statement will be made available on our website.
